Okay, now that we know that our input is
just an object and it has attributes,
one of the attributes that it has is
this value attribute. What is a value
attribute? Well, it's the text that
shows up when you type inside of the
text box that gets stored in its value
attribute. And because it's an object,
we can access attributes and we can
change them. So, I'm going to
demonstrate that by coming back over to
Visual Studio Code, and I'm going to get
rid
of everything here. I'm I'm actually
going to get rid of the script tag for
now, too. And I'm going to have an input
of type text.
And I'm going to give it an ID
of input
box. And I'm going to have another one.
And I'm going to give this one the ID of
output box. Okay, awesome. I have an
input box and an output box. What I want
to do is I want to take whatever they
type in the input box and as they type,
I want to put it in the output box in
uppercase. So in the input box, I'm
going to wait for an event. What event
am I waiting for? Well, I'm interacting
with the user pushing buttons on the
keyboard. So let's look at some of those
buttons. So if I say on key, so it looks
like there are three of them. There's on
key down, on key press, and on key up.
On key down works when the key goes
down. Um, but that means that the value
won't yet have updated because it won't
have fully read the key. It just knows
that a key is going down. Um, what we
want is on key up. When they lift their
finger off of the key, we want to
execute a function. Um, and the function
we're going to execute is called
transfer text.
So when they type in the first box,
every time they lift their finger off of
a key, we want to transfer text. So
let's create our script tag
and let's create our function. So we're
going to say transfer text equals
K. And we want to transfer text from the
first box into the second box. Well, how
do we do that? Well, first things first,
we would need to grab this input box.
So, how do we do that? Well, we need to
use the DOM. How do you use the DOM? By
using the keyword document. So, we're
going to say document.getelement
by ID. So, now we're looking through our
HTML page for an object. And we know
that the object has an ID. And we know
that ID is input box. So we're saying
look through the entire object for an ID
of input box. That will return us this
input tag. This input tag is an object.
If it's an object, it has attributes.
How do you access attributes of objects?
Well, you use the dot notation. So I'm
going to say dot value. So what I've
done is I've said go out to the
document, look through it for an object
or in other words a piece of HTML that
has an ID of the input box and then grab
the value. So right now I'm not doing
anything with it. If I want to use that
value I have to store it. So I'm going
to say let
um input val equal that. So I'm saying
create a new variable. inside of that
variable. I want you to go grab the
input box object and look for its value.
Take that value and store an input
value. And that is how you read um an
attribute out of the HTML page. You
access it using the DOM and then you
access the name of that object's
attribute. Um in this case, the value.
You can also set those similar to how
you would change um if you had an
object, you could change its name
attribute. um we've got an object that
has a value attribute and we can change
that as well. So what we want to do is
we want to change the value inside of
this input. So what we want to do is we
want to say our output box. So we'll say
document.getelement
by ID. What ID are we looking for? Well,
this time we're looking for the output
box.
And then what do we want to do? Well, we
want to access its value. This time
instead of reading the value, we're
going to set the value. So we'll say set
its value equal to um the input value
dot to uppercase. So we're saying take
the input value convert it to uppercase
and store it in the output box. When do
we want this to run? Every time the key
comes up in the input box. So I'm going
to save this and I come to my website
and I'm going to type
my name is Toa. And you can see it took
all of my keys and every time I lifted
my finger off the keyboard, it converted
this entire thing to uppercase and put
it